Victoria, British Columbia, Canada | 250 891 2710

ali.bahrani94521036@gmail.com | Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-bahrani-a6340a127/

CAREER SUMMARY

Software Engineer • Full-Stack Developer • DevOps Engineer

- A young, energetic, and highly resourceful software engineer with 3 years of full-time work experience as
 a software engineer and 6 years of overall experience in web development, supported by a solid
 academic background
- A reliable and communicative teammate who has worked under several agile software development methodologies like Scrum, XP and Kanban
- A proactive problem-solver who provides creative, and efficient solutions for actual enterprise challenges
 in software development and deployment
- Constantly researching for best software development practices to avoid technical debts and code smell and to find the most recent design patterns and software architectures
- Worked with wide range of software development tools including high-level programming languages like python, java, typescript, common frameworks like Django, Spring Boot and Angular and several CI/CD toolsets like GitLab Runner, Jenkins and Circle CI

Key Skills

- C/C++

Python 3

Java

Typescript

SQL Database Design

Django

Spring Boot

Angular

Docker

CI / CD

Microservices

Cloud Native Development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pasargad Electronic Payments, Tehran, Iran

Dec 2019 - Sep 2021

One of the pioneers of e-commerce in Iran. This company is mainly working on e-wallets, internet payment gateways, POS programming, smart city, and several other creative payment methods.

Software Engineer | R&D Engineer

Initially I was hired as a software engineer working on legacy code. After a successful refactor and optimizing the performance of that product, I was offered to form an R&D team to work on modern payment solutions. Simultaneously I continued my duties as a hands-on-code software engineer. Due to moving to Canada we parted ways. These are the tasks that I am mostly proud of.

- Optimization and improving concurrency of a legacy java-based web-service which was initially written by apache mina2 and apache wicket by breaking it into microservices and using multi instances.
- Implementation of a fraud detection system based on gaussian distribution to filter the suspicious banking transactions. We also implemented a RESTful Api using Django and MySQL.
- Changing the deployment pipeline of Smart City team by adding automated testing and modifying the git workflow

• Creating a new e-wallet service using java spring boot, hibernate ORM for backend and typescript and Angular for administration panel

Ponisha, Tehran, Iran

Sep 2016 - Dec 2019

The main freelancer hiring platform in Iran

Freelancer

During my bachelor's degree, I cherished both studying and working. As a result, picking up short-term projects as a freelancer was an ideal job for me. Besides, I contributed to several projects taken from sources other than Ponisha. There is a list of my notable project

- Requirements analysis and applying advanced UML for a wedding revenue website
- *Implementation of a smart web scraper* using python selenium and tor browser to bypass anti-scrapping policy of the web service
- An android book reader app with java and android studio. I also created an XML parser engine from scratch to handle book formatting

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Engineering, Sep 2019 - Present

Iran University of Science and Technology, Iran, Tehran

- Software Major
- The only remaining part is to defend thesis
- GPA 3.67
- Researching on Cloud Gaming Network Latency

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering, Sep 2015 - Sep 2019

Iran University of Science and Technology, Iran, Tehran

- Software Major
- GPA 3.45
- Ranked among top 10% of students, qualified to start master's degree without a fee
- Head teaching assistant of many software courses like the operating systems, languages and automata theory, etc.
- Final project topic: Formal Verification of Smart Contracts in Ethereum Blockchain

Certificates

Academic IELTS 2020

- 7.5
- no skill below 6.5

GRE 2021

- 167 math
- 3.5 writing